Priyadarshana Sarma . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate from Humber College with a degree in Information Technology Solutions, concentrated in Java, REST APIs, and SQL. I have also worked as a Software Engineer at TPF Software India Pvt Ltd, performing various tasks in SDLC such as requirements gathering, component designing (APIs, data model), software implementation (Java and SQL), and testing implemented solutions. Currently, I am a Software Developer at Jarvis Consulting Group, where I have worked on multiple projects in Java, SpringBoot, Linux, SQL, and Docker. Throughout my career history, I've worked in numerous fast-paced and collaborative groups, where to be successful, I always had to learn new things, and also always be dependable to build trust with various stakeholders. I like to follow a loop of improving my skills, being more effective, and contributing more value to my role. I look forward to continuing my journey as a Software Developer.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git Competent: React, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, NoSQL, Express

Familiar: Spring Boot, Microservices, Android Development, REST API, Docker, Python

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_PriyadarshanaSarma

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Developed a Linux Cluster Monitoring Agent using bash scripts that will help to record the hardware specification and monitor the resource usage in a node. The data will be stored in a centralized PostgreSQL database provisioned using docker for monitoring and analysis by the Linux Cluster Administration team. The application was developed and tested on CentOS 7 virtual machine, running on a Google Cloud Platform.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Designed, implemented, tested, and deployed a command line Java application to create, show or delete tweets. The application used Twitter API to interact with Twitter with OAuth 1.0 authentication, SpringBoot for dependency injection, and JUnit and Mockito to test the application, and docker for deployments.
- JDBC App: Developed a Java application that uses JDBC API to perform CRUD operations on a PostgreSQL database. The database is hosted in the docker. The application was built and managed by Maven in Intellij IDE. DBeaver client was used to generating the ER diagram.
- Grep App: Developed a command line Java application to replicate grep functionalities for Windows admins, which takes in the input directory, text to find, and output file. Java stream APIs and Lambdas were used to traverse the root directory recursively to find the matched lines and print the result to the output file. Apache Maven was used for dependency management. Docker was used to deploying the application.

Highlighted Projects

Meeting room reservation system: Built the backend system for a meeting room reservation system which used SOAP and Java Web Methods as the communication protocol. The backend was developed with a 3 tiered architecture and supported all necessary CRUD operations for users to book and manage reservations, and admins to manage rooms.

E-Commerce website for kids wear: Developed "Gift Card", "Customer Profile", and "Contact Us" pages for an eCommerce application using MERN stack architecture. Performed necessary API design and data model for the backend as well as integrations of "Customer Profile" with other pages.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2022-present): Worked as a Software Developer, implementing multiple projects using Java, SQL, bash scripts, and docker as well as ran scrum and participated in all agile ceremonies like a sprint retrospective, and planning.

Software Engineer, TPF Software India Pvt Ltd (2015-2018): Worked as a Software Engineer and performed various tasks in SDLC such as requirements gathering, component designing including REST APIs, data models, software implementation using Java, SQL, and testing implemented solutions using JUnit.

Education

Humber College (2020-2022), Ontario College Graduate Certificate, Information Technology Solutions - Graduated with Honours - Dean's List (Fall 2020, Winter 2021, Fall 2021, Winter 2022) - Percentage: 90.1

Visvesvaraya Technological University (2011-2015), Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication

Miscellaneous

- Swimming
- Board Games